Please turn the lights on in your room and don't get too close to the TV when watching the show.
[Even though it's already over, please pretend it's Christmas while watching this episode.]
[Then please pretend it's New Year's Eve while watching the next episode.]
["People Who Say that Santa Doesn't Really Exist Actually Want to Believe in Him"]
(銀時)だいたい なんで➡
Why do I have to come all the way over here on such a cold night?
こんな寒い日に
こんなところまで…｡
And it's so frustrating having to visit so many stores just to find Nikuman.
[Note: Nikuman = steamed meat bun. And anman = bean-paste bun.]
肉まんくらい置いとけや
腹立つなぁ｡
I should've bought some Anman for myself. I don't even like Nikum...
あ… あんまんも
買っときゃよかったなぁ｡
ｵﾚ 肉まんは あんまり…｡
あ～あ 潰れちまったよ｡
Man, they're all messed up.
(ｻﾝﾀ)あ～あ 潰れちまったよ｡
Man, it's all messed up.
(ｻﾝﾀ)どうすんの？ これ｡
お前のせいだよ これ｡
How could you do this to me?! This is all your fault!
You wrecked my sleigh!
こんな ｿﾘ ﾒﾁｬﾒﾁｬにしちゃってさ｡
Now I can't do anything this year! And it's all thanks to you!
もう 今年 終わりだ これ｡
全部 お前のせいだからな これ！
(ﾍﾞﾝ)ふざけんなよ ｸｿじじい！
坂道 下るときは➡
It's your own fault, you old fart!
We agreed that you'd get off the sleigh whenever we went downhill!
必ず ｿﾘから降りるっていう
約束だっただろうが！
こっちは もう
ｿﾘをひいてるというより➡
I wasn't pulling the sleigh; I was being chased by it!
追われてる感じだったんだよ！
ｱｷﾚｽ腱に ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝ➡
It bashed up my Achilles heels! I'm all bloody!
ｿﾘが当たってんだよ！
血だらけなんだよ もう!!
そんなもん
お前が ｿﾘを上回る速さで➡
Then why didn't you run faster?! Are you a reindeer or a turtle?!
走ればいい話だろうが｡
ﾄﾅｶｲだろうが あん？
お前の親父は
そりゃ すごかったよ｡
Your dad was awesome!
He led the sleigh like a pro, even when we were on hills.
坂道でも
ぐんぐん ｿﾘ 引っ張ってさ➡
He was a real reindeer!
そりゃ 立派なﾄﾅｶｲだった｡
You sound like you liked my dad,
ｱﾝﾀ えらい 親父を
気に入ってるようだけどな➡
親父は 家で ｱﾝﾀの悪口ばっか
言ってたから 言っとくけど！
but when he was at home he only said bad things about you! It's the truth, you know!
You liar. Carl and I were like brothers! Why, I rarely even had to use the whip on him.
(ｻﾝﾀ)ｳｿつくんじゃねえ！
ｶｰﾙと ｵﾚとは➡
主従を超えた戦友だぞ！
(ﾍﾞﾝ)いや ﾏｼﾞで言ってたって！
Seriously, he hated your guts.
His last words were, "His beard is actually brown"!!
遺言が ｢ｱｲﾂ ﾎﾝﾄは
ﾋｹﾞ 茶色｣だったから！
Bastard! Not so loud!
ﾃﾒｴ でけえ声で言うんじゃねえ！
ｸﾘｽﾏｽのときだけ➡
I'll get in trouble if anyone finds out I dye my beard white for Christmas!
白く染めてるなんて知れたら
事だろうが！
ﾃﾒｴで 全部 ﾊﾞﾗしてんだろうが!!
You're the one broadcasting it!
おいおい ちょっと ちょっと…
落ち着けって｡
Hey, hey! Settle down. What are you guys doing?
なにやってんだよ ｱﾝﾀら｡
Shut up!
(ｻﾝﾀ/ﾍﾞﾝ)うるせえ!!
痛っ！
Ow! What the hell are you doing?!
ﾃﾒｴら なにしやがんだ!!
(殴る音)
ったく いいかげんにしなさいよ
こんな夜中にさ｡
Cut it out, you two. It's the middle of the night.
ご近所の迷惑も考えなさいよ｡
People are trying to sleep.
何があったか知らないけどさ｡
I don't know what happened, but...
Well, you beat us up...
いや ｱﾝﾀに
ﾎﾞｺﾎﾞｺにされたんだけど｡
Come on, let's have a drink.
とりあえず 飲みましょうか｡
つうか おたく 誰？
By the way, who are you?
Sake helps facilitate communication between people. It's kind of like a social lubricant.
酒は 人間関係を
円滑にするための潤滑油って➡
かの 徳川 家康も
言ってたような気がしたけど➡
I think Tokugawa Ieyasu said something like that, but I could be wrong.
気のせいだわ｡
Hey buddy, heat up three bottles of sake and some oden.
[Note: Oden = ingredients in soup]
おい 親父 熱燗３本 追加｡
あと おでん 適当に｡
お代は このﾋｹﾞがもつから｡
(親父)へい｡
Give whiskers here the check.
Yes, sir.
(ｻﾝﾀ)ﾋｹﾞって 誰？ まさか ｵﾚ？
(親父)へい｡
Me, have whiskers?! What am I, a cat?!
Here you go.
(ｻﾝﾀ)もう 剃っちまおうかな
こんなﾋｹﾞ｡
I ought to shave them off.
So tell me why you two were arguing. Who are you guys anyway?
で なに？
なんで あんなｹﾝｶしてたの？
つうか おたくら なに？
(ﾍﾞﾝ/ｻﾝﾀ)え？
運送業か何かやってる方ですか？
Are you deliverymen or something?
Well... It's obvious who we are.
あ いや え…
結構 丸出しじゃ…｡
あの… 規則で
あんまりﾊｯｷﾘ言えないんだけど➡
Well, it's against the rules for me to say too much,
but we drive a sleigh and make children's dreams come true.
ｿﾘに乗って
子供たちに 夢を届ける…｡
義賊っぽい感じ？
そうそう そう そういう感じ｡
Like a benevolent thief?
Yeah, yeah sort of... And my name starts with "Sa."
それで ｢ｻ｣の付く あれ｡
"Sa"? Satan?
ｻ… ｻﾀﾝ？
惜しい！
Close! But it has a far better meaning!
けど 遠い｡ 意味合い的には｡
(親父)ﾌﾝ 旦那 よけいな口 挟んで
すいやせんが➡
I know it's none of my business, but I think I have the answer.
あっしは もう わかりやしたよ｡
ほら あれですよ｡
You know what I mean... The hint is hanging between his legs.
ﾋﾝﾄは 股の間に
ぶら下がってる…｡
違うから！ なに そのﾋﾝﾄ！
What?! What kind of hint is that? What kind of answer is that?
いったい どんな答えに
結びつくわけ!?
It doesn't matter if it's Sankon or Santa.
[Sankon, a former diplomat of the Republic of Guinea appeared on many comedy TV shows in Japan. In this case, just a pun of "San"]
まぁいいや ｻﾝｺﾝでもｻﾝﾀでも｡
That's it! One of those was the right answer.
あ いや… 今 １回 言ったよ？
今 １回 正解 言ったよ？
So, you're an old man who rides a sleigh at midnight and does something to children, right?
要するに 夜中に あの…➡
ｿﾘに乗って
子供たちに何かする おっさんか｡
Right... but not quite the way you described it...
(ｻﾝﾀ)そうだけど…｡
なんか ｲﾔなんだけど その言い方｡
I see. I know it's none of my business, but I think I have the answer.
旦那 よけいな口 挟むようで
すいやせんが➡
あっしは もう わかりやしたよ｡
ほら この方たちは➡
They ride around in a sleigh and expose their private parts to people.
ｿﾘに乗って
通り過ぎざまに恥部を露出する➡
あの方たちですよ｡
違えって言ってんだろ！
That's not what I said! You may look like a gentleman, but you have a filthy mind!!
お前 なに ﾀﾞﾝﾃﾞｨな顔して
頭ん中 そればっかか!?
ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄ… ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄだよ｡
Presents! Presents!
ｿﾘに乗って よい子のみんなにね
ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄを配るのが 仕事なわけ｡
I ride in a sleigh and deliver presents to good children. That's my job.
But my sleigh was wrecked, so...
でも そのｿﾘがさ 大破しちゃって
どうにもこうにも…｡
ｿﾘなんて なくたって
仕事くらい できるだろ？
Can't you do your job without a sleigh?
(ｻﾝﾀ)ﾀﾞﾒなんだよ｡ ｿﾘ ﾄﾅｶｲ
赤い服は ｵﾚの三種の神器なの｡
Absolutely not! The sleigh, the reindeer and the red outfit are my trademarks!
ｲﾒｰｼﾞ壊したくないの｡
伝説になりたいの｡
It would shatter people's perception of me if I didn't have them! I'm an icon!
Reindeer? He looks like a monster.
ﾄﾅｶｲって…
これ ただの ﾊﾞｹﾓﾝじゃねえか｡
あぁ!?
なんだか よくわかんねえけど➡
I don't know, but it seems like you're in a fix. Do you need help?
そんなに困ってんなら
力になろうか？
Here's my card.
ｵﾚは こういうもんで…➡
I do anything for my clients. We're "Odd Jobs."
頼まれれば何でもやる
万事屋ってのを やってる｡
I'll help you out, for a price.
払うもん払えば 力になるぜ｡
あぁ？ 何ができるってんだよ？
What?! What can you do?
Can you get us a sleigh right now?
今すぐ ｿﾘを用意できるってのか？
お安いご用だ｡
No problem.
よし 乗れ！
Hop in.
(ｻﾝﾀ)乗れじゃねえよ お前｡
We can't get on that! Its previous occupant is still in it!
なんか 先住民の方が
いらっしゃるじゃねえか｡
Huh? You can see him? He's just "Cardboard" O-san.
えっ？
おたくら あれを見たのかい？
それはねぇ ﾀﾞﾝﾎﾞｰﾙｵｰｻﾝだ｡
He's an elf that only the pure of heart can see.
心がきれいなﾔﾂにだけ見える
妖精さ｡
He can see you, too! He's glaring right at you!
明らかに
お前も見えてんだろうが｡
お前のこと
めっちゃ見てるぞ おい｡
We said we needed a sleigh! This is a two-wheeled cart.
それに ｵﾚたち ｿﾘって言ったの｡
それ ﾘﾔｶｰじゃん｡
(武蔵)ﾘﾔｶｰじゃねえ ﾏｲﾎｰﾑじゃ！
あ すみません｡
It's not a two-wheeled cart. It's my home!
Oh, sorry.
Don't worry about the little details.
細かいことに
こだわってんじゃねえよ｡
Sleigh, two-wheeled cart-same thing. They even sound almost the same.
ｿﾘとﾘﾔｶｰ 言ってみ｡
ほとんど かぶってるだろうが｡
It's not a two-wheeled cart. It's my home sweet home!
ﾘﾔｶｰじゃねえ！ ﾏｲｽｲｰﾄﾎｰﾑじゃ！
あっ すんませ～ん｡
Sorry...
大切なことは何よ？
子供たちに夢を配ることだろうが｡
What's your mission? To make children's dreams come true, right?
Take the back-to-basics approach.
初心にかえれ！ お前ら あの頃
あんなにきれいな瞳を➡
You guys remember how to be idealistic, right?
していたじゃないの｡
お前は ｵﾚの何を知ってんだ!?
What do you know about me?!
だいたい ｲﾒｰｼﾞうんぬん
ぬかすなら ｱﾝﾀの腹のほうが➡
If you're worried about the image of Santa, I think your gut is the problem.
問題だろ あぁ？ ｺﾗ！
こんな腹を見たら➡
Anyone who sees it will think, "He's as pot-bellied as my dad," and be disappointed.
｢あっ お父さんと同じだ｣と
失望すること請け合いだ｡
It's supposed to be like that. I'm an inspiration to all plus-sized people.
いいんだよ これで！
こういう感じなんだよ｡
ｵﾚは ﾃﾞﾌﾞﾀﾚﾝﾄの
先駆け的存在なんだよ！
Red is unflattering on you, too. It makes you look bigger than you actually are.
赤い色は 膨張色といって➡
実際より そのものを
大きく見せちまうんだよ｡
Ditch the outfit. It's ugly. You'd look better wearing something more chic.
とりあえず それ脱げ だせえから｡
もっとｼｯｸな感じでいこう｡
No... I said this is one of my three trademarks! No!
(ｻﾝﾀ)ちょっと…
三種の神器って言ってんじゃん｡
(ｻﾝﾀ)ﾀﾞﾒだって！
ちょっと それ脱いだら➡
Hey, if I take off my outfit, I'll just be an old man.
ｵﾚ ただのじじいに… あぁ～っ！
(鈴の音)
This just...
なんか…｡
違くねえ？
...isn't right.
いやぁ いいよ ｼｯｸな感じで｡
No, you look good and chic.
Just as I thought, black makes you look slim and tranquil.
やっぱ 締まって見えるよ 黒は｡
But it also makes me kind of uneasy, like I should go lock up the house real tight for some reason...
落ち着いた印象を受ける｡
そして なぜだか ｿﾜｿﾜする｡
戸締まり ちゃんとしなきゃ
っていう なぜか…｡
それ 泥棒に見えてんじゃんか！
That's because we look like thieves!!
Nah, more like one of those trendy hipster dads.
あれだよ お前
ちょいﾜﾙｵﾔｼﾞだよ 最近 流行りの｡
These days, throwing a leather jacket on an old geezer makes him look sexy,
片足 泥に
突っ込んでるくらいのほうが➡
even if he's about to croak.
今の時代 ちょいﾓﾃｵﾔｼﾞだよ｡
(ｻﾝﾀ)ちょいﾜﾙじゃないよ これは｡
There's nothing hip about this! I look like a grave robber!!
(ｻﾝﾀ)片足どころか
全身 泥に浸かってるよ｡
泥だらけの棒だよ｡
And you're wearing my outfit! Hey, give it back, right now! Please!
なんか 勝手に着てっしよ～｡
ちょ… ﾏｼﾞ 返してください
お願いしますよ｡
I want to look cool in red this winter!
この冬は 赤で ｷﾒるんじゃい！
You already look cool! You'd look even cooler without my outfit on.
もう ｷﾏってるって
そんなん着なくても｡
ｱﾝﾀ もう 完全に
ｷﾏっちゃってるからさぁ｡
とりあえず この区域 いくか｡
Let's start here. This is a poor residential area, so we should help these people.
ここは 貧しい人が多い｡
救ってやらんと｡
やばいよ これ
誰かに見つかったら➡
Oh, no! If we get caught, it's all over. We'll be reported.
一発ｱｳﾄだよ｡ 即 通報だよ｡
We haven't done anything bad, so why is my heart beating so fast?
なんで 悪いこと
してるわけでもないのに➡
こんなにﾄﾞｷﾄﾞｷしなきゃ
ならねえんだ？
So, who should we start with?
で どいつから
ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄ配ってくんだ？
I'm not visiting any spoiled kids who asked for something like a Nintendo DS or PlayStation.
(ｻﾝﾀ)ＤＳとかＰＳとか
そういうのを期待してる➡
ずうずうしいﾔﾂは なし｡
けん玉とか そういう➡
Let's start with the appreciative kids who only ask for a kendama.
[Note: Kendama is a wooden toy with a ball on a string. You try to get the ball to land on a spike on the handle.]
大人の事情を わかってるﾔﾂ｡
Do you really think you're qualified to make children's dreams come true?
お前ら
ﾎﾝﾄに 夢 与える資格あんの？
Kids today don't want simple stuff like that.
今どき そんな素朴な… おっ｡
Ah...
いたぞ 月島 百合ちゃん｡
I found someone! Yuri Tsukishima-chan.
It's hard to find a kid like her these days...
今どき 珍し…｡
[A kendama and a sweet mother.]
お お母さんは ちょっとﾑﾘだな…｡
A-A mother...is kinda difficult...
(ﾍﾞﾝ)百合ちゃん…
死んじゃったのかな お母さん｡
Yuri-chan... I wonder if her mom died...
(ｻﾝﾀ)ﾍﾞﾝ やめなさい
深入りするのは｡
Ben, don't say that! It's against the rules to make two wishes.
２つも希望があるなんて 反則だ｡
この子は なし！
She won't get anything that way!
(ｻﾝﾀ)他は？ けん玉関係｡
How about the others? Does anybody wish they had something like a kendama?
Why are you insisting on a kendama?
だから なんで けん玉なんだよ｡
Well, I brought lots of kendama toys because I thought it would be all the rage.
(ｻﾝﾀ)あれだよ
けん玉ﾌﾞｰﾑがくると予見して➡
多めに持ってきた｡
ﾔﾏ外れたんだよ｡
But I was wrong. I was right about last year's Korean star boom in Japan though.
去年の 韓流ﾌﾞｰﾑは
当たったんだけどね｡
What kind of presents did you give to children during the Korean star boom?!
韓流ﾌﾞｰﾑなんて
どうやって ﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄしたんだよ!?
…あっ｡
Hey, there might be a kendama boom after all.
おいおい 意外に
けん玉ﾌﾞｰﾑ きてんじゃねえの～？
[A kendama and wings to fly into the future.]
ｵﾚも欲しいよ｡
I want that, too.
Who's next? Who wants a kendama?
(ｻﾝﾀ)はい 次 けん玉関係｡
もういいだろう けん玉は！
Forget about the kendama!
(ｻﾝﾀ)うるせえなぁ ぶっちゃけ
今年は けん玉しか➡
Shut up. Hey, I don't have anything else, but kendama this year!
持ってきてねえんだよ！
もう けん玉にかけるしか➡
So we have to find children who want a kendama!
ｵﾚには ねえんだよ！
ｵﾒｴら➡
You're just an old man who hands out kendama as presents! All right, let's see...
ただのけん玉くれる
おっさんじゃねえか！
よし もう これ最後な！
これ かけるぞ！
Here we go!
(３人)ﾁｷｼｮｰ！
[We played kendama all summer together... I'll never forget that summer.]
He's talking about a toy here, right?
だから けん玉 いらねえだろ！
こらぁ～！
…つうか ｺｲﾂら何歳？
How old is this little sicko?
(ｻﾝﾀ)やべえ！
でけえ声出しすぎた!!
Damn it! We were too loud!
その声が でけえよ!!
この声もでけえ！
You're speaking too loud! Agh! And so am I!
Let's get out of here!
早く逃げ…！
あっ あれ！
Ah... Look over there!
(ﾍﾞﾝ)百合ちゃん！
Yuri-chan!
Yuri-chan wished for a "kendama and a sweet mom."
｢けん玉と 優しいお母さん｣の
百合ちゃんだ！
待ってんだよ あらぁ…｡
She's expecting you to make her Christmas wishes come true. Oh, boy...
ﾃﾒｴらが ｸﾘｽﾏｽの願いを
叶えてくれるって➡
楽しみに待ってんだよ あらぁ…｡
She wrote "a kendama and a sweet mom."
死んじまった母ちゃんと
並べるくらいだ｡
よっぽど
けん玉が欲しいんだろ｡
That means she really wants a kendama.
She might have special memories of it, or something...
なにか 思い出でも
あるのかもしれねえ｡
母ちゃんはﾑﾘだが けん玉なら…｡
We can't do anything about her mom, but a kendama...
行ってやれよ｡
You should do it...
うっ うぅ…｡
Yuri-chan!
(ｻﾝﾀ/ﾍﾞﾝ)百合ちゃ～ん!!
(百合)ｷｬｰ!! お母さん 泥棒～!!
Mom, thieves!
(お母さん)うぅ… おおぉぉ～!!
ちょっ 待っ… お母さん？
お母さん… えっ？
Um... Mom?!
Mom... What?
(ｻﾝﾀ)優しいお母さんに
(爆発音)
戻ってぇぇ～!!
Please return to your sweet mom self!
あぁ… 朝日が昇るよ ﾍﾞﾝ｡
The sun is rising, Ben...
まだ１件も 子供の夢を
叶えてないのに➡
And we didn't even make one child's wish come true yet.
朝日のﾔﾂが
昇ろうとしてるよ ﾍﾞﾝ｡
今年は 最悪だったな｡
This year was the worst.
最後だよ ﾍﾞﾝ｡
このまま帰るわけにはいかない｡
Let's go to the last house, Ben. We can't go home like this.
もうさぁ 貧しい家の
100円ｼｮｯﾌﾟで手に入る夢しか➡
Let's pick a child whose family is so poor that the only toys they get are from the Dollar Store.
もってない子を選んで➡
その子の夢だけ 叶えて帰ろう｡
Then we can bask in that one child's joy and go home.
その子の笑顔だけ 抱いて帰ろう
今年は…｡
万事屋さん お願いします｡
Odd Jobs-san, please.
I already said there's no such kid in this age of gluttony.
だからさぁ 飽食の時代にさ➡
そんなｶﾞｷが
存在するわけな… あ…｡
[Steamed pork bun]
[Odd Jobs Gin]
♪♪～
I'm really sorry.
すみませんねぇ なんか…｡
いやいや いいんだって ｸｯｸｸｸ…｡
No problem.
ｼｯ！
それより 安上がりな
お子様をおもちでお幸せですな｡
Besides, you're very lucky to have a child who likes cheap things.
あれ？ いねえな…｡
やっと ｻﾝﾀらしくなってきたな…｡
Oh? Where is she?
I feel like I'm finally doing my Santa work.
(ﾍﾞﾝ)ｱﾝﾀ 今の自分の姿 見てみろ｡
You should look at yourself in the mirror. You're a thief, nothing but a thief.
ｺｿ泥以外の何者でもねえよ｡
ｸｸｸｸ… これこれ！
(寝息)
Hey!
ｸﾞﾌﾌﾌ… おやおや
ｺﾀﾂでおねむのようですな｡
Oh? She's sleeping under the kotatsu.
[Note: Kotatsu is a low table with an electric foot warmer underneath it, covered by a quilt.]
ｳｼｼｼ…｡
(ﾍﾞﾝ)なに？ このﾉﾘ…｡
What's this? Why are we doing something like Neoki Dokkiri?
[Note: Neoki Dokkiri is an old TV show where the crew visits someone's house and films them waking up.]
なんで 寝起きﾄﾞｯｷﾘみたいな
ﾉﾘになってんの？
A snot bubble!
鼻ちょうちん 鼻ちょうちん…｡
ﾌﾞｯﾊﾊﾊ…!!
なんで こんな
ﾃﾝｼｮﾝ高いの？ このｵｯｻﾝたち！
Why are these guys so excited?
待って待って ｵﾚにもやらせて！
Hey, let me do it.
(ｵﾅﾗの音)
What are you doing?
(神楽)なにしてんだ？ ﾃﾒｴ…｡
What about my steamed pork bun?!
肉まんはどうしたぁ～!?
どおぉぉ～!!
おぉ!!
寝ぼけてる 寝ぼけてる！
She's dreaming! Dreaming! Shoot!
やばい！ 逃げ… わぁ～…！
Gotta get out of here... The Abyss gate is calling me!
うわぁ～！ ｵｴ…！
♪♪～
うぎゃぁぁ～!!
Let go!
離せ！ この野郎！
お前が離せぇ～！
You let go of me!
うわぁぁ～!!
(叫び声)
ｺﾀﾂで寝てしまったｱﾙ｡
Oops, I fell asleep under the kotatsu!
肉まんね！ 銀ちゃん
ﾎﾝﾄに買ってきてくれたｱﾙか！
Steamed pork buns!
Gin-chan kept his promise to buy me steamed pork buns!
♪♪～
(神楽)おいしっ！
Yummy!
["Prayer Won't Make Your Worldly Desires Go Away! Control Yourself"]
♪♪(ｶﾄｹﾝ)｢ｵﾚ ｵﾚ｣
♪♪｢ｶﾄｹﾝｻﾝﾊﾞ｣
♪♪(神楽)｢ｵﾚ ｵﾚ｣
O-le, O-le.
Katoken samba!
♪♪｢ｶﾄｹﾝｻﾝﾊﾞ｣
ｵﾚ～!!
O-le!
Kagura-chan, that's enough. Do you want hot oden all over your face?
(お妙)神楽ちゃん
いいかげんにしなさい｡
ｱﾂｱﾂのおでん
顔に浴びせられたいの？
Right now, I am bald under this wig...
♪♪(ｱｰ子)｢ﾊｹﾞは今 ｶﾂﾗの中｣
(新八)やっぱ 大晦日は
ｺﾀﾂに紅白ですね 姉上｡
There's nothing like watching the Red and White Song Festival while sitting at the kotatsu, Sis.
[Note: The "Red and White Song Festival" is an annual singing competition that is broadcast every New Year's Eve.]
(お妙)そうねぇ｡
父上が健在な頃は➡
Agreed. When dad was alive, the three of us used to enjoy sitting at the kotatsu.
３人 ｺﾀﾂに入って
はじけたものだわ｡
By the way, Gin-san is late.
それにしても遅いなぁ 銀さん…｡
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣合併号
買いに行ったっきりですよ｡
He went out to buy the JUMP double issue.
また事故って 記憶喪失に
なってるんじゃないだろうなぁ｡
I wonder if he had an accident and lost his memory again.
どこぞの娘と
合併でもしてるんでしょ！
He's probably having double fun with a girl. Leave him be.
放っときなさい｡
Your baldness caused by stress...
♪♪(神楽)｢あの ﾊｹﾞは｣
♪♪｢さらすのは｣
(お妙)神楽ちゃん｡
[Note: Chikuwa is fish sausage. One of the ingredients in Oden.]
Kagura-chan, you want hot chikuwa shoved in your nose?
ｱﾂｱﾂのﾁｸﾜ
鼻に突っ込まれたいの？
(銀時/服部)ん？
(服部)なに？ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ合併号？
Eh? What? It's the JUMP double issue.
JUMP double issue. Eh? JUMP double issue?
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ合併号…
えっ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ合併号？
JUMP double issue?
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ合併号？
まいったなぁ…｡
Good grief. There's only one left...
１冊しかねぇ｡
(服部)どうしましょう？
What should we do?
ｵﾚ… かれこれ
ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆ ７～８軒回ったかな？
I've already been to seven or eight convenience stores already.
やっぱ 正月 暇だから
みんな買ってるみたいっすわ｡
Everyone's free during the holiday season, so they are all sold out.
Yeah? Well, I've been to ten convenience stores.
ｵﾚも10軒くらい回ったかなぁ｡
あれ入れたら
ｵﾚ 15軒は行ってるわ｡
Oh, if I include this one, I've actually been to 15 stores.
いや まいったなぁ ﾋﾛｼのﾔﾂがね
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ欲しがってて…｡
Well, my little boy, Hiroshi really wants JUMP.
ｵﾚの息子だけど 今年で５才｡
Hiroshi is my son and only 5 years old.
My mom really wants it, too. She's sick.
ｵﾚは お袋がさ 読みたいって…｡
ちょっと病気でさ
あれ 年越せるかなぁ？
I wonder if she'll see it through the year... In fact, I'm sure she won't.
ﾑﾘだろうなぁ あれ…｡
Well, Hiroshi is also going to die.
あ… 実は ﾋﾛｼも死ぬんだよね｡
ﾋﾛｼ死ぬの!?
Hiroshi is going to die?
まっ そういうことだから
すんません｡
Well...
I want to make his last moments happy.
待て待て待て！ え？ ﾋﾛｼ
ﾎﾝﾄに ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ欲しがってた？
Wait a minute. Wait. What?
Does Hiroshi really want JUMP? JUMP has really gone downhill recently.
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ 最近 落ち目だよ｡
こっちのほうがいいって…｡
I think this one is better.
[Dirty Girls]
いや… ﾋﾛｼ５歳だから…｡
Well... Hiroshi is only five years old.
いや… でもこれ
ﾋﾛｼ読むかもしれないな｡
Well... but Hiroshi might like this... I should buy it... Not for me, just for Hiroshi.
これ… 買ってこっかな…｡
いや… ｵﾚが読むんじゃなくて➡
ﾋﾛｼがさ…｡
(店員)いらっしゃいませぇ｡
Welcome.
いや ちょっと
それ ないんじゃないの？
Hey, wait a minute! That's not fair!
Hiroshi is too young for JUMP. That one is better for him.
いやいやぁ ﾋﾛｼには
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは 早いって！
そっちのほうがいいって…｡
こっちのほうが早いわ!!
He's too young for this!
Honestly, there is no Hiroshi. Hiroshi doesn't exist! Idiot!
…っていうかな ﾋﾛｼなんか
ﾎﾝﾄは いねえんだよ！
この世に存在しねえんだよ ﾊﾞｶめ!!
You're the idiot! I don't have a mom who is dying, either! Stupid! Idiot!
ﾊﾞｶは ﾃﾒｴだ！ ｵﾚだって
死にかけた母ちゃんなんて➡
いないもんね！ ﾊﾞｶﾊﾞ～ｶ!!
Here's the money!
(銀時/服部)はい 金！
ﾃﾒｴ！ いいかげんにしろよ！
You're killing me! You ought be ashamed of yourself reading JUMP at your age!!
いい歳こいて ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟなんて読んで
恥ずかしくねえのか？
ﾋﾟｰﾀｰﾊﾟﾝ症候群か？
Do you have a Peter Pan complex?! No fairy will come for you!
お前なんてな
絶対 妖精寄ってこないから｡
Um...
あの…｡
絶対 陰で悪口言われてるから！
They curse you behind your back.
And who are you to talk, you pathetic JUMP fan you?! Reading JUMP on New Year's Eve!
ﾃﾒｴに言われたかねえんだよ!!
大晦日に➡
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟなんか読みやがって
寂しいﾔﾂだな おい！
Excuse me...
あの！
(２人)えっ!?
Excuse me, but neither of you have enough money.
すみません ２人とも
お金足りないんですけど…｡
(２人)えっ？
(店員)いや… お金が足りません｡
Money. Not enough.
(２人)えぇ？
(店員)２人合わせると➡
Unless you combine your funds. Your decision.
ちょうど足りますけど
どうします？
(近藤)本来なら 大晦日くらい
ﾊﾒをはずして➡
Normally, New Year's Eve is a time to get wild and cut loose.
みんなで騒ぎたいところだが➡
But we have a duty to defend Edo.
我々には 江戸を護るという
使命がある｡
So tonight restrict yourself to one glass.
酒は この１杯だけで
我慢してくれ｡
Just know that I'm proud of you...and of your restraint.
だが 感謝の念なら
ｵﾚが いくらでも注ごう！
Thank you for all your hard work this year!
本当に １年 ご苦労だった！
じゃ みんな
１年 お疲れやんした！
Cheers!
(みんな)乾杯～！
(土方)十分
ﾊﾒはずしてるじゃねえか！
You could use some restraint!
ﾊｧ… ったく
しようがねえ連中だぜ｡
They're hopeless...
Aw, c'mon! It's New Year's! Everything's informal, Hijikata.
(沖田)まぁまぁ 今日は
いいじゃねえですかい｡
無礼講でな 土方よ｡
But you behave informal every day.
ﾃﾒｴは 毎日 無礼講だろうが！
(土方)まぁ いいさ…
今日は ｵﾚ 飲まねえから➡
Oh, well. I'm not going to drink tonight, so you guys have a great time.
ﾃﾒｴら 楽しんでろ｡
[Note: Konoyaro means "you bastard".]
Is there something worrying you, Hijikata Konoyaro?
何か 気になることでも
あるのかい？ 土方この野郎｡
ﾏﾑｼの残党が
不穏な動きしててな…｡
What's left of the Viper's gang is still out there.
And a bunch of bombs are still missing from that warehouse.
倉庫にあった 大量の爆薬も
消えちまったらしい｡
[Snake Killer]
(沖田)頭 ぶった切ったってのに
ｼｯﾎﾟだけで 跳ね回るたぁ➡
It's like a pesky snake that still lives even after we cut off its head.
ﾍﾋﾞってのは しつこくていけねえ｡
I said I'll read this today, and I'll loan it to you tomorrow.
[Oedo Mart]
だからぁ… ｵﾚが 今日 読んで➡
明日 お前に貸すって！
(服部)貸すってなんだ！
What do you mean "loan it"? I paid for half, too. Idiot! You bastard!
ｵﾚも 金 出してんだぞ
ﾊﾞｶ野郎 この野郎！
だいたい ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟって
いったい 何 読んでんだ？
Let me ask you something. Which part of JUMP do you read?
どうせ ２～３本 読んでﾎﾟｲだろ
ｵﾚ 全部 読んでるぞ｡
I bet you just read two or three mangas and then dump it, right? But I read all the mangas.
I love JUMP more than you do.
ｵﾚのほうが 絶対 ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ愛してる｡
What do you know?!
なに言ってんの？ ｵﾚなんか
漫画だけじゃ 飽き足らず➡
I'm not satisfied with reading only the manga,
後ろの 漫画家の
ｺﾒﾝﾄも 読んでんぞ！
so I even read the comments of the manga artists at the end.
編集部の どうでもいいｺﾒﾝﾄも
読んでる！
I even read the lousy editor's comments!
I read about the gift winners, and send in a survey postcard every week.
ｵﾚなんか ｵﾒｴ あのﾌﾟﾚｾﾞﾝﾄの
当選者発表のとこ あんだろ！
あれも全部 読んでる！
ｱﾝｹｰﾄも 毎週 出してる！
甘えな！ ｵﾚは 背表紙裏の➡
That's nothing!
I look over the advertisements for the suspicious mail-order goods on the back.
やや微妙な 通販ｸﾞｯｽﾞの広告まで
きっちり 目ぇ通してる！
And, sometimes I even buy them.
しかも ときどき 買ってる！
Hey, if you don't quit, our issue of JUMP is gonna rip in two.
おい… いいかげんにしねえと
これ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ裂けるぞ やばいって！
いったん ﾀｲﾑしよ…
いったん離せって｡
Damn it! Let's take a timeout. Take your hands off it for now. I promise I won't take it.
ｵﾚ 絶対 取らないから｡
ﾃﾒｴが 先に離せ｡
You take your hands off it first. Then I'll do it.
そしたら ｵﾚも離す｡
ﾃﾒｴ…！
Be an adult! An adult would think about the safety of JUMP!
大人になれよ ここは まず
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟの安全を考えるのが➡
立派な大人の考えじゃないの？
If you take your hands off it, it'll be safe.
ﾃﾒｴが離せば 即 安全確保だ ｺﾗ！
わかった じゃあ 同時に離そう
ｲﾁ ﾆ ｻﾝで 同時に！
All right. Then let's take our hands off it at the same time. OK, counting, one, two and three.
待て ｳｪｲﾄ！ それ
ｻﾝの ｻで 離すのか？
Wait! Do we take our hands off at the "t" or the "e" of three?
ﾝで 離すのか？
ﾝだろ ﾝのほうがあとだ｡
At the "e." After the "e."
At the moment you say "e," or right after you say "e"?
ﾝって言った瞬間か？
ﾝって 言い終わったあとか!?
Huh? I'm getting confused...
あぁっ！ なんか
ﾜｹわからなくなってきた！
(服部)そうだ！ あの
おばあさんに渡そう いったん！
Oh, let's ask that old lady over there to hold it for us.
I'll bet that old boomerang is your spy. You paid her to give it right back to you.
ﾃﾒｴ あのﾌﾞｰﾒﾗﾝばばあ…
お前の回し者じゃねえだろうな！
ﾌﾞｰﾒﾗﾝだけに！
(服部)全然 うまくねえんだよ！
If I could pay an old lady, I'd have bought the JUMP!
どこまで 疑り深いんだ ﾃﾒｴは！
Excuse me, old lady, but could you hold onto this for us?
あの～ すみません おばあちゃん
ちょっと これ➡
預かってもらえますか？
(おばあさん)えっ？
Huh?
Well, I understand that you're a bit surprised, but please?
(服部)えっ てなるのは
わかるけど お願いします｡
ちょっ… 離すつもり
あんのかい？ ｱﾝﾀら！
Hey... Are you guys going to take your hands off it?
おい いいかげんにしろよ！
Hey, hey, cut it out. Even now, you're not going to take your hands off it?!
この期に及んで
まだ離さないわけ？
What are you saying?! I'm all loose and everything.
なに言ってんの？
ｵﾚは もう 虚脱状態だよ？
You're just squeezing it too hard!
お前だろ？ 力 入ってんの！
ぐぬぬぬ… ふんごぉ～っ！
おいぃ！ 離せって!!
Hey! Take your hands off it! Gee! You're gonna kill the old lady!
これ やべえって！
ばあさん 逝っちゃうって!!
Take your hands off it! Why don't you tell her to let go?!
ﾃﾒｴが離せや！ ばばあ もういい！
ﾑﾘすんじゃねえ!!
せいやぁ～っ!!
(銀時/服部)あぁっ！
[Viper Transportation]
I see... The rest of Viper's gang...
(桂)ほぉ… ﾏﾑｼの残党がな…｡
して… 何をやらかす
つもりなんだ？
And... What's their plan?
Rumor is they're going to attack the terminal.
(蕎麦屋)
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ 狙うらしいよ ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙ｡
なんだっけ…
ｼﾞｬｽﾄなんとかっつう➡
Let's see... I heard they'll attack the terminal with a truck full of justa-something bombs.
爆弾 満載したﾄﾗｯｸでよ…
ﾀｰﾐﾅﾙに突っ込むって話だ｡
I can't believe they're going to do it on New Year's Eve.
まぁ 大晦日に ご苦労なこって｡
どう思う？ いけるかね？
ﾑﾘだろうな…｡
What do you think? Will it work?
Not a chance.
なんでよ？
(桂)大晦日も楽しめぬ➡
Why is that?
Any Edoite who tries to get anything done tonight...is bound to screw it up somehow.
無粋な輩に 大事は成せん…
ここは 粋の街だぞ｡
Edo's a party town.
Hey, wait! That JUMP is mine!
待ちやがれ～！
そのｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは ｵﾚんだぁ～っ!!
No!
違う！ あれは ｵﾚのｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟだぁ！
That is my JUMP!
Is he a monster?!
野郎… 化け物か!?
あの身のこなしは…！
He's so agile!
ﾊﾊﾊ… 悪いな にいちゃん！
Sorry, brother!
こう見えても ｵﾚは お庭番衆に➡
I may not look it, but I used to be a member of the Oniwabanshu.
[NOTE: The Oniwabanshu was a group of elite ninjas formed by Yoshimune Tokugawa.]
籍を置いていたことも
あるんで…｡
Hey! Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
だぁっ！ 待て 待て…！
♪♪～
You're trying to get me killed, aren't you?!
ﾃﾒｴ… 他人まで
巻き込むﾔﾂが あるか！
もう ﾀﾞﾒかと思ったぞ…
ちょっと涙目になっちゃったぞ！
I thought I was going to die. I was almost crying, bastard!
この野郎！
ｵﾚのほうが ﾀﾞﾒかと思ったわ！
I'm the one who nearly died! Hell, my life is still flashing before my eyes!
記憶が 走馬灯のように
駆け巡ったぞ！
てか 今も 駆け巡ってんだけど！
It's flashing because we're on a truck!
ﾃﾒｴは 一生
そこで 駆け巡ってろや ﾎﾞｹ！
All right... I'll take...
よっしゃあ！ もらっ…｡
(服部)させるかぁっ！
I won't let you have it!
お前のような 友情 努力 勝利の➡
You don't even understand JUMP's three key principles: "Friendship," "Struggle" and "Victory."
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ三大原則も 心得ねえﾔﾂに➡
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを読む資格は ねえっ！
You don't deserve to read it!
もらったぁ！
させるかっ!!
It's mine!
I won't let you have it!
友情 努力 勝利… ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを読んで➡
"Friendship, Struggle and Victory?"
You think you can master those just by reading JUMP?
そんなものを 手に入れた気分に
なってんのか？
悲しいﾔﾂだ… お前は
自分にないものを➡
Pathetic! You're just trying to fill the emptiness in your life by reading JUMP.
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟで埋めようと
しているだけだ！
You use JUMP as a confidence booster.
慰めてもらおうとしているに
過ぎないんだよ！
JUMP shouldn't be used for that purpose!
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは そんなもんのために
あるんじゃねえ！
♪♪～
Fine... This is the best way for real men.
おもしれえ… 男は やっぱ
ｺｲﾂが いちばん早えよな｡
We'll settle this just as they do in JUMP!
後腐れもねえし
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟでも よくやってるし！
Tsk. I prefer love-comedy manga to battle manga.
ﾁｯ… ｵﾚは ﾊﾞﾄﾙ漫画より
ﾗﾌﾞｺﾒのほうが 好きなんだがな｡
But I have no choice. Sometimes a man must fight for his love!
しかたない 愛を通すには
戦わなきゃならねえこともある！
Gintoki Sakata.
坂田 銀時！
服部 全蔵…｡
Zenzo Hattori.
(２人)参る！
(衝撃音)
Now!
...What? Did I just hear a weird noise?
(益次郎)なんだぁ？ 今 なんか
変な音 しなかったか？
I wonder if the cops know we're here...
まさか 幕府の犬に➡
嗅ぎつけられたわけでは
あるまいな…｡
Don't worry, it's New Year's Eve and even cops are partying tonight.
(勘兵衛)いらぬ心配だ…
どいつも こいつも➡
今日は 大晦日で
浮かれ 騒いでいよう…｡
Besides, this truck looks perfectly ordinary,
まして 外から見れば
なんの変哲もない こんなﾄﾗｯｸに➡
恐るべき爆弾が
搭載されていようとは➡
so people will never guess it's equipped with a fearsome bomb.
誰も 夢にも思うまい…｡
もうじき 江戸は火の海さ… ﾍﾍﾍ｡
Edo will soon be a sea of fire.
えっ… なっ！
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを… 返せえぇ！
JUMP...
Give it back to me!
(勘兵衛)うわぁ～！
(益次郎)勘兵衛～!!
Ka-Kambei!
うっ!?
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟを…➡
JUMP...
Give it back to me!
返せえぇ！
♪♪～
"Friendship, Struggle...
《友情 努力 勝利…｡
...Victory"...
よく わからねえが…》
《まんざらでもねえな…》
I don't exactly get it, but...
Those aren't bad...
なんて思うかぁ！
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは ｵﾚのものだぁ！
I'll never think of it that way!
This JUMP is mine!
(鐘の音)
Big sister, what kind of noise do you hear?
ｱﾈｺﾞ さっきから ｺﾞﾝｺﾞﾝ ｺﾞﾝｺﾞﾝ
この音は 何ｱﾙ？
Is that a student preparing for his entrance exams by banging his head against the wall?
受験生が 壁に頭を
打ちつけているｱﾙか？
No, Kagura-chan.
違うわよ 神楽ちゃん｡
That's the sound of businessmen who've been downsized throwing themselves out windows.
これは ﾘｽﾄﾗされたｻﾗﾘｰﾏﾝが
岩を叩いて➡
拳を鍛える音よ｡
姉上 何を教えてるんですか!?
Sis... What are you teaching her, anyway?
いいじゃない 子供に
夢を与えるには ｳｿも必要なのよ｡
It's all right. When you give a child something to dream for, sometimes you have to lie.
Well, your idea of revenge doesn't leave much room for hope and dreams.
いや 夢も希望もないですから
そんな復讐譚！
神楽ちゃん これはね
除夜の鐘といってね➡
Kagura-chan, that's the New Year's Eve bell.
毎年 大晦日の夜には➡
They ring that bell 108 times on New Year's Eve.
こうして 鐘を108回
打ち鳴らすんだよ｡
108 times? No wonder they're jumping out windows!
(神楽)108回も!?
受験生に対する嫌がらせｱﾙか？
108というのは 人間の煩悩の数｡
108 symbolizes the number of a person's earthly desires.
つまり 欲望の数と
されていてね…｡
Each time the bell is struck,
鐘を鳴らすことによって
その煩悩を➡
another desire is struck from your heart, so you can start the new year fresh.
１つずつ 打ち消して
まっさらな きれいな心で➡
新年を迎えようっていう
そういうことなのさ｡
Kagura-chan, your heart is already clean, so you don't need it.
神楽ちゃんは 心がきれいだから
必要ないわよね｡
でもね 人間 大人になると
どんどん そういう汚いものに➡
But as people grow up, they become more greedy for things.
心が とらわれやすくなって
しまうものなの…｡
(お妙)神楽ちゃんも 新ちゃんも➡
Kagura-chan, Shin-chan. I hope you two don't grow up like that.
そんな汚い大人になっちゃﾀﾞﾒよ｡
(お妙)煩悩に捕らわれた人間に
待つのは➡
Desire leads only to ruin.
滅びのみよ…｡
J-JUMP is...
(銀時/服部)ｼﾞ… ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟは…➡
ｵﾚのもの…｡
mine...
あれ…？
Oh?
[AKAMARU JUMP]
これ よく見たら…｡
Looking at it up close...
赤ﾏﾙ ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟじゃん…｡
...it's just AKAMARU JUMP.
(鐘の音)
[Preview]
Heavy snow?
The spirit of an Edoite is to enjoy every occasion!
The next episode: "Only Children Play in the Snow." Let the Kabukicho Snow Festival begin!
[Hasegawa-san created this snow statue titled, "Flight."]
[Another episode will be: "Eating Ice Cream in Winter Is Awesome."]
We're looking forward to continuing the series this year!